Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある兄･六太と
ひびと
栄光の日 生まれの弟･日々人＞
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
＜日本人初のムーンウォーカーと
なった日々人の遥か後ろから➡
Older brother Mutta continues his long quest to the moon, having finally been selected as a backup member.
月を目指し始めた兄･六太は
ついに月のミッションに➡
任命された｡一方 月面での事故の
影響でパニック障害となり➡
A lunar accident has left Hibito struggling on the sidelines, suffering from a panic disorder.
But he's able to pass a test to return to active duty.
前線から外された日々人は
復帰試験をなんとか乗り越えた＞
＜しかし 一度パニック障害と
なった以上 復帰への道筋が➡
However, NASA decides that Hibito,
having succumbed to panic disorder, cannot be assigned to a mission,
開かれることはないと判明｡
日々人は姿を消したのだった＞
and Hibito disappears.
I can't get lost in what I'm doing, nothing works out
I don't want these endlessly dull days
I hope I can move on
before the call of freedom drags me away
What's your wish?
I just want some real courage
We all stare doubt in the face, every one of us
Isn't the unpredictability of life the fun of it?
Devote your life to that dream you can't express
Let's go, advance against the wind, our road is long
Embrace the pain of it too
Take a big breath now, and yell
Big Bang! Chase it without fear!
I want to dream so badly it amazes me
There's cowardice in the way of your true wish
Rip that hot veil aside
#98 The Ultimate Astronaut
(南波母)今回は当たるわよ～｡➡
I'm gonna hit the jackpot this time...
だってね そこの宝くじ売場で
買うと当たるって話を➡
Because everyone said that store sold to lots and lots of winning people!
多々聞くのよ 多々！
クリーニング屋の古川さんが
５０万円でしょ～！
Furukawa, from the laundry place, won 500,000 yen.
仏壇屋の島田さんて言う人なんか
５枚買っただけで➡
And Shimada, from the Buddhist place, bought five tickets, and won 300,000 yen.
３０万円当ったらしいのよ～！➡
そろそろ出るわよ これお父さん！
億！億！億！ど～しよぉ！
I can feel it coming, dear...
Billions, billions, billions!
What will we do?
(南波父)｢多々｣って…｡
２件でもう多々か｡
Lots and lots?
Two winners count as "lots and lots"?
２件もありゃ 多々でしょ～！
Two is a lot!
｢多｣と｢々｣！
Lots and lots.
(南波六太)ちょっと母ちゃん！
Hey, Mom!
日々人がまたいねぇんだけど｡
こんな時間なのに｡
Hibito's missing again, and it's dark outside.
あらまた!?
しょっちゅういなくなる奴だ｡
What? Again?
He wanders off lots and lots.
L-Lots and lots? He's only done it twice!
しょっ…しょっちゅうって
まだ２回目じゃん｡
なにのんびりしてんのさ
２人とも！
How can you guys be so relaxed?
２回もやってりゃあ
しょっちゅうだ｡
Two is a lot.
｢しょっ｣と｢ちゅう｣｡
Lots and lots.
俺 ちょっと外見てくる！
I'll go out and look for him.
う～ さむっ！
It's freezing...
くっそ～ どこ行った～ 日々人～｡
Man... Where did Hibito go?
《なんで何も言わねぇで 勝手に
どっか行くんだよ お前は！》
Why do you have to run off without saying anything?
現在
(ビンス)ミスター ムッタ｡➡
Mr. Mutta.
Are you listening, Mr. Mutta?
聞いてますか
ミスター･ムッタ｡
ん…あっ はい
聞いてます すみません｡
Oh, yes. Sorry, I'm listening.
誰のためのミーティングか
わかってないようですね｡
It appears that you don't understand who this meeting is for.
さっきのシミュレーションの
交信は 全くかみ合って➡
During the last simulation, communication was a jumbled mess.
いませんでした｡
君はこちらに伝えるべき情報を➡
You omitted information you should have transmitted to me,
一部言い逃していますし
私が話し出したところに➡
and you also lose points for interrupting me while I was talking.
声をかぶせて流れを
中断させたのも➡
マイナスポイントです｡
はい…｡
Right.
(ラリー)《まっ 普段から
ガンガンかぶせて➡
It's funny because Vince is usually the one who's constantly interrupting people.
人の話 中断すんのは
ビンスだけどな》
我々は息が合ってなければ
なりません｡
We must be in sync at all times.
(ﾋﾞﾝｽ)さっきのような
乱れた交信をしていたら➡
If there is any miscommunication, we will be unable to follow the procedure manual.
本番でマニュアル通りの工程を
踏めなくなります｡
次からはしっかり集中して下さい｡
Next time, try to concentrate harder.
気のゆるみはミッションの
失敗だけでなく…｡
A moment's lapse can lead to a mission failure,
事故にもなつがると言うことを
再認識して下さい｡
or even cause an accident.
はい…｡
Yes.
《はぁ～…やっちまった》
I screwed up...
《初日あたりは
うまくいってたのに…》
On the first day, I did fine...
《確かに ここんとこ
集中できてねぇな 俺…》
But I've been having trouble staying focused.
｢もう君は宇宙へは行けない｣と➡
Did you tell Hibito that he can't go to space anymore, Butler?
日々人にそう説明したんですか？
バトラーさん｡
(バトラー)いや そこまで露骨には
言わなかったが…｡
No, I wasn't that blunt about it.
ヒビトには
そう聞こえたかもしれん｡
But that's probably how Hibito interpreted what I said.
今日も来てないみたいですよ｡
先週の金曜日からだ｡
He hasn't shown up since last Friday.
《チクショー 無視かよ
日々人のヤロー》
Damn...
Hibito's ignoring me?
《返信くらいして来いってんだよ》
He could at least send a reply.
《日々人がいなくなって
今日で６日目》
It's been six days since Hibito vanished.
《ご近所さんも➡
I've asked the neighbors,
日々人と親しい
ナサ
ＮＡＳＡの連中も➡
his NASA friends,
父ちゃんや母ちゃんでさえも➡
Mom and Dad...
誰一人 日々人の居場所を
知るものはいなかった》
But no one knows where Hibito is.
た～いま｡
I'm home...
(南波日々人)あっ ムッちゃん｡
寝よ～か｡
Hey, Mu.
Let's go to bed.
寝よ～かじゃねぇだろ！
Is that all you have to say?
ふあぁ～…ごめん ごめん｡
Sorry about that.
おとめ座の写真撮ろうと思って
公園まで行ってたんだ｡
I went to the park to take pictures of Virgo.
But all I got was a bunch of dark pictures.
結局 真っ暗な写真しか
撮れなかったけど 見てみる？
Wanna see?
《くっそ～…》
Man...
今度また勝手にいなくなっても
もう捜しに行かねぇからな 俺｡
If you wander off again, I'm not gonna look for you.
Sorry, I'll let you know next time.
ごめんってば｡
次は行く前に言うからさ｡
あっ それかあれ…
メモ書いとくよ｡
Or I'll leave a note.
"Hey, hey! I'm in the park right now, Mu!"
俺は今 公園にいるよ～！
ムッちゃ～ん！って➡
That's the message I sent you with telepathy.
テレパシー送ってたんだけど
聞こえなかった？
You didn't hear it?
聞こえるか アホッ｡
How could I hear that, fool?
じゃあさ！じゃあ今
俺 何考えてるでしょう？
Okay, then do you know what I'm thinking now?
送ってるよ～！
I'll send it over!
ウ～ン ウ～ン…｡
《知るかよ めんどくせぇ》
How would I know, stupid?
ウ～ン…｡
はぁ～… この➡
You want me to teach you how to take pictures of Virgo with a camera.
このカメラでおとめ座を
うまく撮る方法を教えてほしい｡
え？うわぁ～すげぇ！正解！
すげぇな ムッちゃん！
Wow, you're right!
That was amazing, Mu!
言っとくけど
そのカメラじゃ無理だ｡
Just so you know, it isn't possible with that camera.
やっぱ通じるじゃん テレパシー！
So telepathy works!
俺もすげぇんだな フフッ｡
I guess I'm just as amazing.
じゃあこれからは
テレパシー使うわ｡
Then from now on, I'll use telepathy.
現在
帰って来ねぇ気か｡
まあ別にそれでもいいけど｡
Is he not coming back?
I guess that's fine with me.
だってこんな広い家を
一人じめだ！
Since I'll have this huge house all to myself.
And I can drink all the beer.
ビールも一人じめ！
遠慮なく歌えるぅ～
And I can sing all I want!
見れるぅ～
And I can watch whatever I want on TV!
あの これさ➡
Hey...
お礼ってわけじゃないけど…｡
There isn't any particular reason for this, but help yourself.
よかったら飲んでよ｡
おやおや 気なんか使わんで
いいんだぞ ムッタ｡
What's this about?
This isn't necessary, Mutta.
へへ ありがとう｡オジー オバー｡
明日もよろしく｡
Thanks Ozzy, Ova.
See you tomorrow.
ああ もちろん｡
Yep, sure thing.
おやすみ～｡
Good night!
(オバー)おやすみ ムッタ｡
(オジー)おやすみ｡
Good night, Mutta.
Good night.
まだ帰ってないみたいね｡
あの様子じゃ｡
Looks like Hibito still isn't back.
Yeah...
そうだな…｡
(オジー)まさかあのヒビトが
いなくなるなんてな｡
I didn't expect Hibito to go missing.
[TV]♬～
[TV](ｷｬｽﾀｰ)明日のテキサス州は
大体晴れ！➡
Tomorrow, we're looking at sunshine in Texas.
With some clouds rolling in, and a chance of rain.
もしくは曇りだが…
雨が降ることも考えられる｡
But if you keep a smile on your face, rain can't force the sunshine away.
[TV]だけど もし君が
笑顔でいてくれたなら➡
たとえ雨が降ろうとも
それは｢晴れ｣なんだよ！
[TV](ｷｬｽﾀｰ)でね もし君が…｡
And if you start crying, you'll be raining on any sunny day.
誰だ この番号？
I don't recognize this number.
Hello?
Oh, Mr. Mutta.
[ｹｲﾀｲ](ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)ああ ミスター･ムッタ｡
私だ｡バトラーだ｡
It's me... Butler.
えっ…バトラーさん？
B-Butler?
I've been getting concerned because it's been a few days since Hibito came in.
この数日 ヒビトが
来ないようだから気になってな｡
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)まあ 彼に直接電話しても
よかったんだが｡➡
I could have called him directly,
私とは話したくないかもしれんと
思ってな｡
but I thought he might not want to talk to me.
何か…あったんですか？
Did something happen?
やはり 聞いてはいないか｡
Then he didn't tell you anything.
[ｹｲﾀｲ](ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)ナンバ･ヒビトは医学的な
適性は満たしている｡➡
Medically, Nanba Hibito is fit.
宇宙飛行士としての実績も
申し分ない｡だが…➡
He meets all the requirements for an astronaut.
But...
ＮＡＳＡとしてはこの先
あえて彼を月ミッションに➡
NASA has concluded that sending him back to the moon on a mission
任命するようなリスクを
負うべきではないという➡
isn't worth the risk.
結論に至った｡
《なんでそういうこと
何も言わねぇで➡
Why did you run off without saying anything to me?
勝手にどっか行くんだよ
お前は！》
《約束のメモも
書かないままで…》
And you didn't leave a note like you promised.
《どこ行った!?》
Where are you?
なんとか言えよ日々人…｡
Say something, Hibito.
テレパシー使えんだろ｡
I thought you could use telepathy.
全然聴こえてこねぇんだよ！
I can't hear a thing!
ど どういう事ですか？
What do you mean?
だって
日々人は復帰試験を受けて…｡
Didn't Hibito pass the test to return to duty?
発作も出ずにやり終えて➡
He completed the test without an attack.
あれは…合格ということじゃ
ないんですか？
Doesn't that mean he passed?
試験中 日々人の心拍数が
上がる場面があった｡➡
During the test, there was a point when Hibito's heartbeat jumped.
まあ 宇宙飛行士なら誰でも起こす
レベルの乱れではあったが➡
Of course, this happens to all astronauts...
それを発作の一部だと解釈する
試験官も数名いたんだ｡
But a few of the examiners considered this the sign of a panic attack.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)その内の１人が
ﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑﾏﾈｰｼﾞｬｰときてる｡➡
One of them is the program manager.
彼の同意なしに
日々人を任命するのが➡
I'm sure you can see that, without his approval, Hibito can't be assigned to a mission.
不可能だという事は
君でもわかるだろう｡
ﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑﾏﾈｰｼﾞｬｰって
あのゲイツって人ですよね？
Is the program manager that Gates person?
じゃあ俺から話して
あの人さえ説得できれば…｡
So if I talk to him and convince him to change his mind...
[ｹｲﾀｲ](バトラー)
いや 余計な事はやめておくんだ
ミスター･ムッタ｡
No, you don't want to do that, Mr. Mutta.
すでに日々人の現場復帰を願う
嘆願書だって揃ってたんだよ｡
There's a petition requesting Hibito's reinstatement.
上から目をつけられるのも
覚悟の上で➡
Four veteran astronauts signed it,
４人のベテラン宇宙飛行士が
署名までしてくれた｡➡
knowing that they would be subjecting themselves to scrutiny.
ダミアンにフレディ エディ･Ｊ
そしてアズマもだ｡
Damian, Freddy, Eddie Jay, and Azuma.
吾妻さんも…｡
[ｹｲﾀｲ](バトラー)だが➡
Azuma...
But that still wasn't enough.
そんなベテラン達の声さえ
届かなかったんだ｡➡
君はでしゃばるべきではない｡➡
You should keep your mouth shut.
ヘタをすれば今度は君が 月への
チャンスを奪われかねないんだ｡
One wrong move, and you could lose your chance to go to the moon.
バトラーさん｡➡
Butler...
ＮＡＳＡに意思があるとして
その目で見たら 日々人は…｡
Does NASA truly believe...
that Hibito is...
アホみたいに天気いいな｡
The weather's too nice.
早く着きすぎたし…｡
I came too early...
クソッ…日々人 まさかケータイ
失くしたとかじゃねぇだろうな｡
Damn.
Hibito, don't tell me you lost your cell phone.
"Hibito...
I don't even know if you're still alive.
Give me some kind of reply.
《｢面倒なら
“あ"だけでもいいぞ｣》
If you don't want to bother, an "A" will work.
Even Mom and Dad are beginning to worry.
If you don't message us, they'll ask the police to start searching for you.
Tell me if you're alive or dead."
フン まっ こういう日々人が
つっこみそうな➡
I even added a light joke that Hibito won't be able to ignore.
ソフトなボケもおりまぜつつ…
送信！
Send.
[TV](ビンス)
キャプコム
こちら着陸船アルタイル｡➡
CAPCOM, this is landing module Altair.
燃料の残量は
23351キログラム｡➡
We have 233,351 kilograms of fuel remaining.
この数値は
規定より少なくはないか｡
This should be sufficient.
確認します｡
Let me confirm.
この燃料の減りは想定内だ｡
ミッションはＧＯだ｡
Fuel consumption is within expected levels.
The mission is a go.
想定内の減りです｡
問題ありません｡
Fuel consumption is within expected levels.
You're doing well.
[TV](ビンス)了解｡
Roger that.
ちょっと 手洗いに行ってくる｡
(ダミアン)あ はい｡
I need to run to the restroom.
Oh, okay.
ありがとう ダミアン｡
Thanks, Damian.
日々人の復帰願いの嘆願書に
署名までしてくれて｡
I heard you signed a petition requesting that Hibito be reinstated.
当然のことだ｡
I only did what was right.
ヘマして動けなくなった俺が
また月へ行けるのに➡
After a near fatal mistake, I've received the chance to return to the moon.
助けてくれたヒビトが
行けないなんて➡
It makes no sense that Hibito wouldn't be allowed to return, after saving me.
そんな ふざけた話は
ないと思ってる｡
《そうだ…やっぱり
こんな扱いはおかしい！》
Yeah...
This makes no sense at all.
《１人の人間が積み上げてきた
ものを…何だと思ってる！》
Don't they understand how hard he worked to get here?
《俺の弟のことを
何だと思ってる！》
Do they not have any respect for my brother?
[TV]キャプコム
こちらアルタイル｡
CAPCOM, this is Altair.
おわっと！
はい こちらヒューストン！
Er, yes! This is Houston.
全ての逆噴射ノズル稼動を確認…｡
Confirm that all thruster nozzles are operational.
Thruster...
Er, yes! This is Houston!
おわっと！
はい こちらヒューストン！
Crap, I interrupted him again.
《しまった！
またかぶせちまった》
Is it okay to leave the thruster angle and output on setting A?
[TV](ビンス)
噴射角及び出力数値は
今の｢設定Ａ｣で問題ないか？
Let me confirm.
確認します｡あ…｡
Ah.
Right, the flight director isn't currently here.
《そうか
今 ﾌﾗｲﾄﾃﾞｨﾚｸﾀｰいないのか》
ええ～っとですね…｡
Let's see...
《ここはいつも
設定Ａでやってるよな》
Is setting A standard procedure?
Well?
[TV](ビンス)どうなんですか？
はい｡だ 大丈夫です！
Yes, it should be fine.
設定Ａでお願いします｡
Use setting A.
[TV](ビンス)
了解した｡
これより着陸態勢に入る｡➡
Roger that.
We will now commence landing sequence.
高度2300メートル｡
Current altitude is 2,300 meters.
(ビーッ ビーッ…)
警報が鳴り出した｡
A warning has sounded.
状況を確認してくれ｡
Please confirm.
予定の着陸ポイントから
離れていってる｡
We're heading away from the designated landing spot.
このままだと３０キロ先の
山脈地帯に➡
At this rate, we'll have to land in a rocky area, thirty kilometers away.
着陸せざるを得なさそうだが
どうする？ヒューストン｡
What do we do, Houston?
(ラリー)どうする？ヒューストン｡
あ あれ!?
What do we do, Houston?
Huh? What?
《何でだ!?》
こちらの表示で見ても
同じ見解だ｡
Why?
We confirm the warning.
安全に着陸できそうな
ポイントを探して また連絡する｡
We will search for a safe landing area, and communicate it to you.
キャプコム これは何事だ！
CAPCOM, what's going on?
[ｹｲﾀｲ]バトラーさん｡➡
Butler...
ＮＡＳＡに意思があるとして
その目で見たら➡
Does NASA truly believe...
that Hibito is an unfortunate and weak person?
日々人は不運な弱者に
見えますかね？
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)えっ いや
決してそんな事はないが…｡
N-No, certainly not.
[ｹｲﾀｲ]俺の目で見た日々人は
真逆です｡
In my mind, Hibito is the exact opposite.
月の事故では 暗闇の谷底から
仲間を救い出し➡
After the lunar accident,
he saved his fellow crew member from the bottom of a dark ravine,
最善の判断で
無事 生還しました｡
making all the right decisions to return alive.
その後のパニック障害も➡
Afterward, he demonstrated that he had conquered his panic disorder.
持ち前の根性で
克服して見せたんです｡
日々人は 他のどの宇宙飛行士
よりも 本当の恐怖を知っていて➡
Hibito knows the fear of being in space better than any other astronaut,
それを乗り越えた男です｡
and he has overcome that fear!
今のあいつは俺から見れば
最強の宇宙飛行士です！
If you ask me,
he is the ultimate astronaut.
現在
私も…そう思う｡
I feel
the same way.
もしもし バトラーだ｡
Hello, this is Butler.
ほしか
お久しぶりです｡バトラーさん｡
It's been a while since we last talked, Butler.
直に電話をくれるとは
珍しいな｡➡
It's unusual for you to give me a call,
ミスター･ホシカ｡
Mr. Hoshika.
Are you available to meet right now?
今からどこかで会えませんか？
I'm in Houston for a meeting on asteroids.
小惑星関係のミーティングで
ヒューストンに来てるんですが｡
南波日々人君のことについても
お話を…｡
I'd like to talk to you about Nanba Hibito.
The starlight illuminates my future, it's wow... truth
It's 3 AM, and I dream awake
With no idea of my future
only impatience consumes me
I have a thorn in my heart that won't allow me to lose to him
I'm walking a path of thorns I made for myself
But I won't forget the love I found
And I won't forget the ones close to me
I realized you cannot live your life alone
The starlight illuminates my future, and we are all shooting stars
My holy wishes turn all our sad lies into something better
Our orbits have gotten separated,
but I'm fine if you are close
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#99 People Change,
Promises Don't
Hibito has yet to return.
＜姿を消したまま
戻らない日々人＞
＜そして 今 宇宙飛行士としての
未来をめぐり➡
But he has made a decision about his future as an astronaut.
日々人の下した決断が
明らかになる＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"People Change, Promises Don't"
Mr. Hibbit!
《はあ～ 最後に一度でも➡
I was hoping for one last bite of a space carrot...
｢宇宙ニンジン｣
食べてみたかったな～》
《ん!?なんだこの光 まぶしい！》
Wh-What's this light?
I can't see...
あっ 君は まさか!?
Are you...
Sorry, I was curious about Earth's technology, so I was fiddling around your base.
ごめんよ
地球の技術が興味深くて➡
基地の中をたくさん
かじってしまったけど➡
悪気はなかったんだ｡
I meant no harm.
お詫びに これをあげるよ｡➡
As an apology, I'll give you this.
食べてごらん｡元気が出るよ｡
Take a bite.
You'll feel better.
《な なんだこの味は!?》
I-It tastes great!
イェーイ!!
Yay!
えっ？あ あれ？
Huh?
(ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨｺﾞﾘﾗ)ンジャマ～～!!➡
ムワッ！ウホッ ウホッ！
(ｶﾚﾝｷｬｯﾄ)ニャ！
大丈夫か!?ヒビット！
You okay, Hibbit?
(ﾚｯｻｰﾘﾝﾀﾞ)ヒビットォ！
Hibbit!
(ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝﾎｰｸ)いたぞ！
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨﾄﾞｯｸﾞ)ヒビット｡
There he is!
Hibbit.
(ｶﾚﾝｷｬｯﾄ)私に任せて！
Let me look at him.
うわっ 痛っ！
(ｶﾚﾝｷｬｯﾄ)ﾆｬｯﾆｬｯﾆｬｯ ﾆｬﾆｬﾆｬ…
ニャッ！
不思議 異常がニャいわ｡
Strange... Nothing's wrong with him.
フフフッ 月ウサギが
助けてくれたんだ！
The moon rabbit saved me.
なんだって？
あら やっぱり
異常あるのかしら｡
What?
Oh, it appears something is wrong with him.
僕らは
ここへ来た甲斐があったよ！
It was totally worth the trip up here!
Let's fix up the base quick...
すぐに基地を修理して➡
彼らを探しに行こう！➡
And go find them!
彼らはきっと
この月のどこかにいるんだ！➡
I'm sure they're somewhere on the moon.
待ってろよ！月ウサギ！
イェ～～イ!!
Wait for us, moon rabbits!
Yay!
And that's the end!